Guide to the Cave Canem Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Cave Canem records
1995-2012
JWJ MSS 130
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
27.29
(30 boxes)
The Cave Canem Records contain correspondence (including electronic mail), organizational records, photographs, financial records, computer files, and audiovisual recordings that document the activities of Cave Canem Foundation, Inc. and its founders Toi Derricotte and Cornelius Eady. The organization's governance, fundraising, publicity, and operations are documented as well as its publishing activity, fellowship program, and Legacy Conversations series, which features poets and scholars who have played historic roles in African American poetry. The collection serves as a resource for scholarship on African American poetry, literature, and culture in the twentieth and twenty-first centuries.
Cave Canem (Organization)
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I. Operations, Fundraising, and Governance, 1997-2012. II. Programs, 1996-2011. III. Publishing, 1996-2011. IV. Promotional Material and Collateral Literature, 1996-2011. V. Photographs, 1997-2010. VI. Audiovisual Material, 2002-2011. VII. Digital Media. VIII. Restricted Material.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 28 (audio and video cassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 29 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 30: Restricted until 2033 August 1. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
Cave Canem (Organization)
Cave Canem, a nonprofit organization dedicated to cultivating the artistic and professional growth of African American poets, was founded in 1996 by Toi Derricotte and Cornelius Eady.
Scope and Contents
The Cave Canem Records contain correspondence (including electronic mail), organizational records, photographs, financial records, computer files, and audiovisual recordings that document the activities of the Cave Canem Foundation, Inc. and its founders Toi Derricotte and Cornelius Eady. The organization's governance, fundraising, publicity, and operations are documented as well as its publishing activity, fellowship program, and Legacy Conversations series, which features poets and scholars who have played historic roles in African American poetry. The collection serves as a resource for scholarship on African American poetry, literature, and culture in the twentieth and twenty-first centuries.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James S. Jaffe Rare Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund and the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts & Letters Fund, 2013.
Related Materials
Toi Derricotte Papers (YCAL MSS 1219). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Cornelius Eady Papers (JWJ MSS 146). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
African American poets -- 20th Century; African American poets -- 21st century; American poetry -- African American authors; American poetry -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 21st century; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 21st century; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Photographs; African American poets -- 20th Century; African American poets -- 21st century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 21st century; Derricotte, Toi, 1941-; Eady, Cornelius, 1954-; Cave Canem (Organization)
- Operations, Fundraising, and Governance, 1997-2012; Series I; 5; (5 boxes)
  - Testimonials
    - Elaine Shelly, 2000 March 8 (Box 1)
    - Lillien Waller, 2002 February 23 (Box 1)
    - Samantha Thornhill, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
    - Nagueyalti Warren, 2003 November 2003 (Box 1)
    - Prize Winners, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Shane Book, undated (Box 1)
    - Remica Bingham, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Opal Palmer Adisa, 2002 January 16 (Box 1)
    - Toni Brown, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Jacqueline Johnson, 2001 March 23 (Box 1)
    - M. Eliza Hamilton Abegunde, 2002 February (Box 1)
    - Samiya Bashir, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Nelson Demery, III (Jericho Brown), 2002 February 18 (Box 1)
    - Erica Doyle, 2001 February 8 (Box 1)
    - Phebus Etienne, 2002 April (Box 1)
    - John Frazier, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Joy Gonsalves, 2003 December (Box 1)
    - Hallie Hobson, 2004 March 16 (Box 1)
    - Lita Hooper, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Tyehimba Jess, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Lauren Alleyne, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Brandon D. Johnson, 1998 November 6 (Box 1)
    - John Keene, undated (Box 1)
    - Raina J. Leon, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Toni Asante Lightfoot, undated (Box 1)
    - Carrie McCray, 2000 September 30 (Box 1)
    - Dante Micheaux, 2003 November 19 (Box 1)
    - Lenard D. Moore, 2000 December 31 (Box 1)
    - Mendi Lewis Obadike, 2001 March 20 (Box 1)
    - G. E. Patterson, 1998 February 26 (Box 1)
    - Hermine Pinson, 1999 November 22 (Box 1)
    - Nancy Mebane Shakir, 1999 January 28 (Box 1)
    - Holly Bass, 1999 April 15 (Box 1)
    - Shia Shabazz Barnett, 2003 December (Box 1)
    - Tara Betts, undated (Box 1)
    - Gloria Burgess, 2002 March (Box 1)
    - Curtis Crisler, 2003 November 24 (Box 1)
    - Robin Caudell, 2002 March 9 (Box 1)
    - Traci Dant, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
    - Eisa Davis, 2001 March 27 (Box 1)
    - Jarvis DeBerry, undated (Box 1)
    - Krista Franklin, undated (Box 1)
    - Kendra Hamilton, undated (Box 1)
    - Reginald Harris, 1998 November 6 (Box 1)
    - Yona Harvey, 1999 July 12 (Box 1)
    - Terrance Hayes, 1998 November 5 (Box 1)
    - Sean Hill, 2002 May 18 (Box 1)
    - Z'etoile Imma, 2003 March 15 (Box 1)
    - Valerie Jean, undated (Box 1)
    - Honorée Fanonne Jeffers, 1998 November 5 (Box 1)
    - Patricia A. Johnson, 2002 July 26 (Box 1)
    - Douglas Kearney, undated (Box 1)
    - M. Nzadi Keita, 2002 February 24 (Box 1)
    - Doughtry Long, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Kenyetta Lovings, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Charles H. Lynch, 2005 February (Box 1)
    - Toni Asante Lightfoot, undated (Box 1)
    - Devorah Major, 1999 March 8 (Box 1)
    - Adrian Matejka, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Evie Shockley, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Dante Micheaux, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Sheree Renee Thomas, undated (Box 1)
    - Venus Thrash, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Tracy Smith, undated (Box 1)
    - Christopher Stackhouse, undated (Box 1)
    - Afaa Michael Weaver, 1998 November 6 (Box 1)
    - Damon Williams, undated (Box 1)
    - Karen Williams, 2002 February 24 (Box 1)
  - Financial records, 1997-2011 (Box 1)
  - VA Depart. Coinsurance, 2005 (Box 1)
  - 501 C3/ Governance information, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Virginia- sales and use tax exemption, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Virginia Department of Taxation- withholding, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Virginia- charitable registration, 2001 (Box 1)
  - '97 Grant Information- research, organization, drafts
    - Sources of funds, articles, lists of donors, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Proposals sent and replies, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Proposals to send or explore, 1997; 2 (Box 1)
    - Grant proposals still outstanding, probably dead, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Proposal drafts, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Guidelines from funders not approached, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Funder chart, summary of outstanding requests, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Rejected grant requests, 1997; 2 (Box 1)
    - Grant writing help, the Foundation Center information, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Letters to funders not answered, considered dead, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Cave Canem Proposal Information Draft, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Budget Reports
    - Annual report, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Program report, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Program report, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Annual budget, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Director search
    - Job search, 1999 September (Box 1)
    - Search ads, 1999 August (Box 1)
    - Interviews, set up and questions, 1999 October 19 (Box 1)
    - Job candidates, no interviews, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Job candidates, 1999 September-October (Box 1)
    - Email and phone calls, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Job applicants, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Job description, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Board meetings
    - Meeting, 1998 February (Box 2)
    - Advisory board, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1999 June 24-25 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 1999 June 24-25 (Box 2)
    - Money and timeline, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 1999 April 16 (Box 2)
    - Handouts from meeting, 1999 February 13 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, extra copies, 1999 (Box 2)
    - New board members correspondence, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Financial report, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Strategic plan, mission, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Board and request package, 1999 July (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1999 June 24 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Director's list, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, preparation, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 2000 January 22 (Box 2)
    - Handouts, 2000 January 22 (Box 2)
    - Search for treasurer, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Strategic plan, 2000-2002 (Box 2)
    - Members list, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2000 June 24 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 2000 June 24 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2000 August (Box 2)
    - Vote, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Advisory board, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2003 June 21 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2003 June 21 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2003 April 10 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2003 February 7 (Box 2)
    - Vote on stock, 2003 February 6 (Box 2)
    - Corporate resolutions, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2003 December 6 (Box 2)
    - Packet sent for board meeting, 2003 November (Box 2)
    - Meeting, June 21 2003 (Box 2)
    - Agenda and handouts, 2003 December 6 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2003 December 26 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2003 June 21 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 2004 June 19 (Box 2)
    - [Update with Reports Fords?], 2004 February 13 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2004 June 21 (Box 2)
    - Mailings, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Strategic plan report, 2004 February (Box 2)
    - Meeting notice, 2004 June (Box 2)
    - Strategic plan, 2004 February (Box 2)
    - Confidentiality/management policy- confidentiality agreement, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Board nominating committee, research regarding board terms and end of term letters, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2002 December (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2002 November 2 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 2002 November 2 (Box 2)
    - Vote, 2002 May (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2002 June 22; 2 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2002 August 20 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2002 July 9 (Box 2)
    - Handouts, 2002 June 22 (Box 2)
    - Board retreat, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Board fundraising training, 2002 November 2 (Box 2)
    - Member list, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Strategic plan implementation, undated (Box 2)
    - Annual budget, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Financial reports, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Mailings, 2004 December; 2 (Box 2)
    - Letter, 2004 September 2 (Box 2)
    - Ballot, 2004 Februrary 17 (Box 2)
    - Member list, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2004 December 11 (Box 2)
    - Agenda, 2004 December 11 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2004 June 19 (Box 2)
    - Ballot for board of directors, 2005 May (Box 2)
    - Board Reminder, 2005 April 27 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 2005 December 10 (Box 2)
    - Members, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Strategic plan, 2000-2002 (Box 2)
    - Budget vote, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, finances and report, 2001 December (Box 2)
    - Vote, 2001 December (Box 2)
    - Vote, 2001 August (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2001 August 3 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, preparation, 2001 June 23 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2001 June 23 (Box 2)
    - Handouts, 2001 June (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2001 February (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 2001 February 17 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, preparation, 2001 February (Box 2)
    - Meeting, finances, 2001 February 17 (Box 2)
    - Director's report, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Mailing, 2001 March (Box 2)
    - Votes, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, 2001 June (Box 2)
    - DeLoach, treasurer, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Reception, 2001 October 24 (Box 2)
    - Advisory board, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Job description, 2005 (Box 2)
    - February update, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Biographies of new board members, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Board mailing, 2005 October 14- November 1; 3 (Box 2)
    - Board retreat planning, 2005 October (Box 2)
    - Mailing to new board members, 2005 August 3 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 2005 September-December; 6 (Box 2)
    - Bylaws, master, 2005 May 24 (Box 2)
    - Board member biographies
      - Reese, Henry, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Semple, Robin, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Swiggett, Ernest, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Hayes, Terrance, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Jones, Hettie, 2008 (Box 2)
      - LaMon, Jacqueline Jones, 2010 (Box 2)
      - Lewis, Juliet, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Morris, Tracie, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Brown, Marie Dutton, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Cooper, Desiree, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Derricotte, Toi, 2008-2009 (Box 2)
      - Eady, Cornelius, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Gabbin, Joanne, 2008 (Box 2)
      - Gargani, Francis, Fr., 2008 (Box 2)
      - Gillespie, Fern, undated (Box 2)
      - Griffin, Farah Jasmine, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Resolutions
      - Authority to sign legal documents, 2006 November 11 (Box 2)
      - Resolution, 2007 November 10 (Box 2)
      - Jennie McKean Moore Endowed Fund: withdrawal of principal, 2008 January 23 (Box 2)
      - Remote vote to re-elect Tracie Morris to 2008-10, 2008 September 22 (Box 2)
      - Resolution to authorize ED to sign NYS grant, 2008 (Box 2)
      - BOA savings account signatory, 2008 May 14 (Box 2)
      - Vote for board candidates, 2008 April; 2 (Box 2)
      - Remote vote for budget, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Fundraising grant applications
    - Proposal or letters outstanding accepted, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
    - Altman Foundation, 1999 (Box 3)
    - American Express Matching Gift, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
    - American LIbrary Association, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Annenberg Foundation, 2003 (Box 3)
    - AOL Time Warner, 2000-2002; 4 (Box 3)
    - AT&T Foundation, 2002-2005; 3 (Box 3)
    - ASTRAEA Foundation, 2003 March (Box 3)
    - Bama Works, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Axe-Houghton Foundation, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Bank of America, 1999-2009; 8 (Box 3)
    - Barnes & Noble, 2002-2005; 3 (Box 3)
    - Bloomberg, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Borders, 1999; 2 (Box 3)
    - Boyd's Mill Press, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Breneman Jaech Foundation, 2001-2002; 2 (Box 3)
    - Buhl Foundation, 2005 (Box 3)
    - The Bydale Foundation, 2002-2003; 2 (Box 3)
    - Carolyn Foundation, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Charlottesville-Albemarle Community Foundation, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Circuit City Foundation, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Robert Sterling Clark Foundation, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Comerica Incorporated, 2001-2002; 2 (Box 3)
    - Con Edison, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Center for Humanities, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Daimler-Chrysler, 2000 (Box 3)
    - New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, 2006-2008; 2 (Box 3)
    - Detroit Edison Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
    - Irene Diamond Fund, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Dodge Foundation, 1999-2006; 18 (Box 3)
    - DTE Energy Foundation, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Doris Duke Charitable Foundation, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Educational Foundation of America, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Exxon Mobil, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Ford Foundation, 1997-2005; 12 (Box 3)
    - Mrs. Giles Whiting Foundation, 1998-2005; 7 (Box 3)
    - GAEA Foundation, Inc., 2002 October (Box 4)
    - Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation, 1999-2008; 8 (Box 4)
    - General Motors, 2000 (Box 4)
    - GreenPoint Bank, 1997-1999; 3 (Box 4)
    - GreenPoint Foundation, 2001-2004; 4 (Box 4)
    - Greenwall Foundation, 2001-2003; 4 (Box 4)
    - Gudelsky Foundation, Inc., 2002 (Box 4)
    - The George Gund Foundation, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Heathcote Foundation, 2002 (Box 4)
    - The Heinz Endowment, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Henry Holt & Company, Inc., 1997-1998; 2 (Box 4)
    - Hewlett-Packard Company, 1997 (Box 4)
    - HIP USA, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Independence Community Foundation, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Jerome Foundation, 1997-2004; 11 (Box 4)
    - The J.M. Kaplan Fund, 2002 (Box 4)
    - J.P. Morgan Chase, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Lannan Foundation, 1997-2001; 2 (Box 4)
    - LEF Foundation, 1999-2003; 4 (Box 4)
    - Lilly Endowment, 1999-2003; 2 (Box 4)
    - Madison Madison International, 2001-2002; 2 (Box 4)
    - MASCO Corporation, 2001-2003; 3 (Box 4)
    - The McGraw-Hill Companies, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Michigan Council for Arts and Cultural Affairs, 2000-2002; 5 (Box 4)
    - Morris and Gwendolyn Cafritz Foundation, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Multicultural Arts Initiative, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Nathan Cummings Foundation, 1997-2003; 3 (Box 4)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 2000-2004; 9 (Box 5)
    - Network of Cultural Centers of Color, 2005 (Box 5)
    - New York Community Trust, 2003-2004; 2 (Box 5)
    - New York State Council on the Arts, 1999-2003; 4 (Box 5)
    - New York Council on the Humanities, 2003; 2 (Box 5)
    - North Carolina foundations, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Oak Hill Fund, 2003-2004; 2 (Box 5)
    - Peter Norton Family Foundation, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Pew Charitable Trusts, 2003 (Box 5)
    - The Philadelphia Community Foundation, 1999-2002; 3 (Box 5)
    - The Pittsburgh Foundation, 2003-2004; 2 (Box 5)
    - The Poetry Foundation, 2004 (Box 5)
    - Poets and Writers, Inc., 2002-2003; 2 (Box 5)
    - The Reed Foundation, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Robert Sterling Clark Foundation, 2001-2003; 2 (Box 5)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1998-2004; 2 (Box 5)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
    - Proposals to promising donors, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Roy A. Hunt Foundation, 2004 (Box 5)
    - Rubin Foundation, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Rush Philanthropic Arts Foundation, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Sara Lee Foundation, 1999 (Box 5)
    - The Scherman Foundation, 1999 (Box 5)
    - The St. Paul Foundation, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Suntrust Bank, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Taproot, undated (Box 5)
    - Target Foundation, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Third Wave Foundation, 1999-2001; 3 (Box 5)
    - Time Warner, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Twenty-First Century Foundation, 1999-2000; 2 (Box 5)
    - United Way of New York City, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Universal Studios Foundation, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Vanguarde Media, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Viburnum Foundation, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Virginia Commission for the Arts, 2002; 2 (Box 5)
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities, 2002; 3 (Box 5)
    - Wallace-Reader's Digest, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Wallace Fund, undated (Box 5)
    - Wachovia, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Wellspring Foundation, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Whole Foods, 2004 (Box 5)
    - Wilbur Foundation, 2003 (Box 5)
    - William Bingham Foundation, 2003 (Box 5)
    - William Randolph Hearst Foundation, 2004 (Box 5)
    - The Witter Bynner Foundation for Poetry, 1999-2002; 2 (Box 5)
  - Computer disks relating to operations, undated; 4 floppy disks (Box 29)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Box 29 (Computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Scope and Contents
    Computer disks that have been separated from the files in Series I. for preservation purposes.
- Programs, 1996-2011; Series II; 8; (8 boxes)
  - New York City class, 1999; 4 (Box 6)
  - Personnel policies poet's house, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Russell Goings thank-you note, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Reading at Mt. St. Alphonsus, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Philadelphia benefit reading, 1999 (Box 6)
  - New York City reading, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Poet's House free 10 week workshop, 1999 Spring (Box 6)
  - Schomburg workshop, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Borders Books invite, 1999 February (Box 6)
  - Workshop submissions and replies, 1999 (Box 6)
  - New York City and Minnesota classes, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Minnesota evaluations, 2000 (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop evaluations, 2000; 2 (Box 6)
  - Reunion, 2000 (Box 6)
  - First Books, reading, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Calendar, 2000 (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop recipients, 2000 Fall (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop applicants, 2000 Fall (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop feedback, 2000 Fall (Box 6)
  - Twin Cities workshop, 2000 (Box 6)
  - New Orleans reading, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Tracie Morris resume, 2000 (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop, 2000 Fall (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop, 2000 Spring (Box 6)
  - Poets and Writers, 1998-2000 (Box 6)
  - Newsletter collection request, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Festival of the Book, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Grant proposal for documentary program, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Poetry prize, 2000-2001; 2 (Box 6)
  - First Books reading, correspondence, flyers, and programs, 2001 Spring (Box 6)
  - Michigan benefit, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Twin Cities workshop series, 2001 Spring (Box 6)
  - Minnesota, correspondence, 2001 (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop series, 2001; 2 (Box 6)
  - Poet's House workshop applicants, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Reading schedule, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, reading, 2001 (Box 6)
  - People's Poetry Gathering, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Festival of the Book, public relations and correspondence, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Reunion (Philadelphia reading), 2001 (Box 6)
  - 14th St. Y, 5th anniversary for Cave Canem event, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Pratt reading, Toi & Cornelius- Baltimore, MD, 2001 (Box 6)
  - A conversation and reading with Lucille Clifton and Sonia Sanchez, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Twin cities evaluations with Toi Derricotte, 2001 Spring (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop evaluation, 2001 Spring (Box 6)
  - New York City workshop evaluation, 2001 Fall (Box 6)
  - Minnesota evaluations, 2001 Fall (Box 6)
  - An Evening of Poetry, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Back-up files, 1 floppy disk (Box 29)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Gwendolyn Brooks Memorial Reading, 2001 (Box 7)
  - New York City workshop, 2002 Spring (Box 7)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem reading, 2002; 2 (Box 7)
  - Poetry workshop reading, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia reading, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Loft Literary Center workshop, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Sonia Sanchez and The Academy: one day conference, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Museum of African American History, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Pratt Library, 2002 (Box 7)
  - The Academy of American Poets, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Reading and Poetry Prize event, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Montclair reading, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Lyrae's tour, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Reunion, 2003 (Box 7)
  - AWP reading, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Legacy conversation and reading, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Studio Museum of Harlem, 2003; 2 (Box 7)
  - VA Festival of the Book, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Minnesota master class, 2003 (Box 7)
  - New York City workshop with Cheryl Clarke, 2003 (Box 7)
  - New York City workshop with Erica Hunt, 2003 Fall (Box 7)
  - New Jersey workshop with Willie Perdomo, 2003 Fall (Box 7)
  - Warhol Museum, 2003 (Box 7)
  - 10th Anniversary, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Sample reading invitations (Box 7)
  - Cave Canem at the Warhol, retreat, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Obadike, 2006 Spring (Box 7)
  - Wisher, 2006 Spring (Box 7)
  - New Jersey workshop with Tracy K. Smith, 2005 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey workshop II with Phebus Etienne, 2005 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey workshop applicant submissions, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Norfolk State University reading, 2011; 2 (Box 7)
  - Cave Canem Brings the Drama!, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Workshops, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Madhubuti/Elizabeth Alexander reading, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Legacy: Harryette Mullen/ Lorenzo Thomas, 2004 (Box 7)
  - New York City workshop with Quincy Troupe, 2004 Spring (Box 7)
  - New York City workshop with Patricia Spears Jones, 2004 Fall (Box 7)
  - New Jersey workshop with Cheryl Clark, 2004 Fall (Box 7)
  - Letter regarding Herman Beavers participation in the Black Writers Conference, 2004 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey workshop, 2004 Speing (Box 7)
  - Minnesota master class, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Legacy conversations
    - Elizabeth Alexander/ Haki Madhubuti, 2004 (Box 7)
    - Video proposal, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Video: Harper and Weaver, transcription, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Harper-Weaver conversation transcript, 2003 March 13; 1 3.5 inch disk (Box 29)
    - Video: Thomas and Mullen, release statement, 2004 (Box 7)
    - Video distributors, undated (Box 7)